# Xiaoxuan(Sherley) Qin

xiq33@pitt.edu | xiaoxuaq@andrew.cmu.edu

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate graduate student with research interests in Network/Information Security and Privacy. My research has involved enhancing wireless network protocols through machine learning techniques and ensuring secure data transmission in the quantum world. Additionally, my studies have also delved into Human-Computer Interaction. I have hands-on experience in network protocol analysis, penetration testing, wireless access exploitation and have participated in cybersecurity competitions such as NCL and CTF. And I am positively confronting emerging challenges, striving to contribute to the academia and the society.

#### **NOTABLE SKILLS**

Programming Language: Python, JAVA, R, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, LaTeX

Research Tools: Network: NS-3, Wireshark, Nmap, Nessus, Metasploit, Aircrack-ng; Data Management: Hadoop,

MySQL, Hive

**English Proficiency:** TOEFL: 112 (R: 28, L: 30, S: 24, W: 30)

#### **EDUCATION**

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA 09/2023 – till present

Visiting Student
Research Area: Cybersecurity

Core Courses: Introduction to Cryptography

#### **University of Pittsburgh**

Pittsburgh, PA

Master of Information Science(ongoing)

09/2022 - till present

Tentative GPA: 3.81/4

Research area: Network Security and Information Security

Core Courses: Information Security and Privacy: A, Network Security: A, Application of Network: A-, Algorithm

Design: A, Machine Learning: A

#### **Hubei University of Economics**

Wuhan, Hubei

Bachelor of Management in Information Management and Information system

09/2017 - 06/2021

Overall GPA: 3.7/4.0

Core Courses: Linear Algebra 88, Business Statistics I/II (Probability): 95/93, Data Structure: 91, Java I: 85, Java II: A+, Database System: A+, Data Communication: A+, Web Application Development: A+, Mobile Application

Development A

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Enhancing Neighbor Discovery in Wireless Sensor Networks Using Deep Learning Techniques

03/2023 - present

#### **Research Scope:**

The primary objective of this research is to explore the potential of employing deep learning techniques, specifically Multi-Layer Perceptrons (MLP) and Graph Convolutional Networks (GCN), in enhancing the Searchlight Protocol, aiming to reduce the latency of neighbor discovery and improve energy efficiency within a Wireless Sensor Network (WSN).

#### **Achievements:**

- Conducted a detailed comparative analysis of various neighbor discovery protocols in WSNs, successfully
  pinpointing Searchlight as a potential candidate for enhancement in neighbor discovery by deep learning
  techniques.
- Undertook an extensive comparison of two selected deep learning models, considering the trade-off between prediction accuracy and computational resources in neighbor discovery.
- By integrating the chosen deep learning model into the Searchlight protocol in the WSN with edge computing, the performance of neighbor discovery was effectively enhanced, ensuring more accurate and efficient neighbor discovery.

## **On Post-Quantum Key Establishment**

04/2023 - 08/2023

Supervisor: Prof. Krishnamurthy, Prashant Venkata (University of Pittsburgh)

## **Research Scope:**

The research focuses on how to enhance the secure data transmission in a post-quantum world of mixed post-quantum and pre-quantum secure flows through the **key pre-distribution** method.

#### **Achievements:**

- Proposed a key pre-distribution scheme to enhance the security of communications in a post-quantum world.
- Formulated a **probability model** to evaluate **the probabilities of successful key matches** between non-post-quantum and post-quantum nodes under varying key pre-distribution.
- Devised a simulation-driven key pre-distribution mechanism, culminating in an empirical model to guarantee finding a shared key between two heterogeneous nodes (a non-post-quantum node and a post-quantum node).
- Introduced **two strategies** to help **quickly build a secure connection** between a non-post-quantum node and a post-quantum network.

**An Empirical Study on the Impact of E-commerce Application User Interface Design** 02/2021 - 06/2021 **Supervisor**: Prof. Zhu, Xiaobo (Hubei University of Economics)

## **Research Scope:**

This study aimed to delve into the determinants of **user experience** within E-commerce platforms by examining **interface and interaction design**, integrating **emotion** as an intermediary variable. The research specifically targeted a broad age demographic from **16 to 65** and utilized UI Design Elements and Emotional Factors with Taobao's User Experience as the primary evaluation benchmark to build a research model.

#### **Achievement:**

- Developed a research model that identifies Interface Design and Interaction Design as primary variables, and Emotional Factors as intermediary variables, using Taobao's User Experience as the evaluation object.
- Quantified the influence of UI design on user satisfaction and recommended specific enhancements to mobile UI design to improve the user experience measurably.
- Awarded "Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis"

### ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

#### **PPG Project based on Machine Learning**

03/2023 - 04/2023

Advisor: Dr. Yurko, Joseph (University of Pittsburgh)

### **Description:**

• Developed machine learning models to predict the important property and classify the popularity of paint

colors based on inputs from two color models: RGB and HSL.

## **Responsibilities:**

- Performed regression analysis and classification using both non-Bayesian and Bayesian linear models to
  decipher the influence of color model inputs on a concealed paint property and to discern the popularity
  of paint colors based on color model inputs.
- Trained and tuned models with more complex methods such as Generalized Linear Model, Elastic Net, Neural Network, Random Forest, SVM, and Gradient-Boosted Tree.
- Tested model performance using RMSE, Accuracy (for classification), and ROC (for classification) to ascertain the most effective predictive model.
- Leveraged the selection of the best models to successfully identify key variables that had a strong impact on the important paint property and the popularity of paint colors.

## **Database System for E-Commerce**

10/2022 - 12/2022

### **Description:**

A database system designed as an online perfume and body-care shopping system, which displays six
categories of products with eight types of scents - aiming at providing customers with a good online perfume
and body-care shopping experience.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Database Design (MySQL): Designed and implemented a comprehensive e-commerce database comprised of 10 entities and 10 relationships between them.
- Customer Interface Development (Flask): Developed a comprehensive customer interface, that allow customers to register, log in, modify personal information, browse and search items by category or scent, add products to their shopping cart, and complete checkout process securely.
- Manager Interface Development (Flask): Designed a comprehensive management portal for site
  administrators, enabling them to view product details, update product information, manage product availability,
  and monitor sales data.

(Project available at: https://github.com/Qin99113/22fall infsci2710 project)

#### **Enhancement of Canvas Search Engine**

09/2022 - 12/2022

Advisor: Prof. He, daqing (University of Pittsburgh)

### **Description:**

• As an Everyday Study Management Platform used by college students, Canvas provides search functions in different modules, like "Assignment", "Discussion", etc, separately for a particular course. However, it has no global search function across different modules, also students are not able to search in detail for specific content. This project is attempting to design a global search engine that can target all the details in all the modules on canvas, including words in PPT or WORD the instructor or the TA issued.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Contributed to addressing the challenge of insufficient global search capabilities, i.e., through enhancing the ability of the search engine to access and retrieve data from the entire platform of a specific course.
- Perfected the Search Algorithm of Canvas to increase its breadth and precision, implementing both exact search algorithm **and fuzzy search algorithm (BM25)** and evaluated by **MAP**, which recorded [relatively] a high score of **0.837**
- Refined search results display mechanism to provide users with more relevant, accurate, and intuitive results: this helped to enhance user experience and boost **user satisfaction** nearly by 50%.

## Big Data Analysis of Taobao's Singles Day Sales

01/2019 - 02/2019

Advisor: Wenli Zhang (Chinese Academy of Sciences)

### **Description:**

• The project is aimed at harnessing the vast amount of consumer data from Taobao's Singles Day sales to extract strategic intelligence, with the goal of enabling the creation of highly targeted marketing campaigns and enhancing customer experience.

#### Responsibilities:

- Constructed a Hadoop cluster on a Linux system, built a Hive data warehouse to store 7027945 pieces of data, and then built MySQL relational database to run real-time query and information visualization, and integrated them using Sqoop for efficient data transmission.
- Quantified and subsequently visualize consumer behaviors, preferences, and expenditure levels segmented by age, gender, and region during Taobao's Singles Day, providing a robust data-backed foundation for crafting personalized marketing strategies.

#### TEACHING ASSISTANT

### **Programming Essentials for Business Analytics (Fall 2023)**

- Instructor: Dr. Ahmad, Altaf (University of Pittsburgh)
- Credit 3; 491 undergraduate students
- Course website: <a href="https://catalog.upp.pitt.edu/preview-course.php?catoid=213&coid=1175721">https://catalog.upp.pitt.edu/preview-course.php?catoid=213&coid=1175721</a>

### PRACTICAL EXPERIENCE

## Hangzhou Xiaomawang Education Technology Co. Ltd.

05/2021- 02/2022

#### Lecturer of Python Programming

- Instructed students in Python programming, starting with fundamental concepts, followed by data structures, then progressing through algorithm development, modular programming, front-end design, and data scraping and culminating in AI programming.
- Guided nearly 90% of students to achieve the Level 3 Python Certificate endorsed by the China Institute of Electronics and received almost 100% positive feedback from students.

SAP China 08/2020 - 09/2020

## PTA of Intelligent Manufacture Project Group

- Developed in-depth analysis of Dissona's Value Stream Mapping, which encompassed customer and market demand, production management, and supply chain system management, and identified critical process bottlenecks.
- Designed and implemented robust information systems (CRM, ERP, SCM, MES) tailored to optimize
  process and resource management, thereby effectively resolving bottlenecks identified through Dissona's
  Value Stream Mapping, culminating in a 100% successful transformation towards an intelligent
  workshop.
- Attended AI+CRM products seminar, discussing how to integrate AI with CRM to realize personality service to increase efficiency and manage risks.

#### **AWARDS & HONOURS**

Canglong Student Scholarship (Twice) (Top 10%); Specialized Scholarship (Top 5%)

## **REFERENCES**

## Prof. Krishnamurthy, Prashant Venkata

School of Computing and Information

University of Pittsburgh Email: prashk at pitt.edu

Webpage: <a href="https://sites.pitt.edu/~prashk/">https://sites.pitt.edu/~prashk/</a>

## Dr. Jain, Aayush

School of Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University

Email: aayushja at andrew.cmu.edu

Webpage: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/aayushjain/home">https://sites.google.com/view/aayushjain/home</a>